<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Health Tips</string>
    <string name="text">

MOUNTAIN POSE
 \n\n
This yoga pose helps with balance and grounding through the feet.
Stand tall with your big toes touching and heels together.
Draw your abdominals in and up and relax your shoulders down and back.
Breathe five to eight breaths.
\n\n

TREE POSE
\n\n
Excellent for leg and abdominal strength. Good for seniors for balance
and concentration. Stand tall and place one foot on the opposite inner
thigh, either above or below the knee. Open the leg to the side, bring
your hands to a prayer position and hold for five to eight breaths.
\n\n

BIRD DOG POSE
\n\n
Good for abdominals and back support. The health of the spine is extremely
important as we age. Start by kneeling and stretching one arm forward and
the opposite leg back. Imagine you have a tea cup on your back and draw your
belly button towards your spine. Stay for a breath and then switch sides. Repeat
five times.
\n\n

DOWNWARD FACING DOG POSE
\n\n
This position is great for joint health, flexibility and all-over body strength.
Start on your hands and knees, tuck your toes under and lift your hips up and back
until your body forms a triangle. Use your core strength and legs to bring the weight
back as much as possible. Stay for five to eight breaths, lower yourself down, and
repeat two more times. For seniors with wrist issues, try the Forearm Downward Dog instead,
putting your forearms flat on the mat.
\n\n

SPHINX
\n\n
Excellent for upper back strength and preventing forward head syndrome. Sphinx is gentle
and really does a great job of opening up the chest and working the rear deltoids.
Lie down on your stomach and place your forearms on the mat, elbows under your shoulders.
Press firmly into your arms and draw your shoulder blades together and down your back. Lift
your abdominals in and up and stay for five to eight breaths.
\n\n

COBBER POSE
\n\n
This is a great way for seniors to keep their hips open and massage their feet. Sit
tall and bring the soles of the feet together as you open your knees out to the sides.
Fold yourself forward for a deeper stretch but try to prevent rounding too much in the
lower back. Hold for five to eight breaths.
\n\n

SAVASANA
\n\n
Savasana resets the nervous system and helps with restoring peace to the body and mind.
Lie on your back in final relaxation. It’s good for seniors to get comfortable with
letting go more often throughout the day. Lie down and let the floor support you.
Completely relax the muscles and breathe as you lie there and take a deep, restorative break.




    </string>
    <string name="text1">
        1. Foods Rich in Omega-3
\n\n
Omega-3 fatty acids are known to have anti-inflammatory properties that
help to reduce the risk of cancer, arthritis, health issues, and rheumatoid
arthritis in old age. It also prevents other age-related problems like poor
vision, depression, anxiety, and reduces the risk of Alzheimers which is
common in old age. All these qualities make Omega-3 rich foods a crucial part
of a balanced diet chart for people in older age. It is mainly found in the
following foods:
\n\n
  ● Fish: Rawas (Indian Salmon), Mackerel and Tuna\n
  ● Dairy: Eggs, Milk, SoyMilk, and Yoghurt (Dahi)\n
  ● Grains and Nuts: Flax Seed (Alsi), SoyBean, Kidney Bean (Rajma), Oatmeal (Dalia)\n
  ● Vegetables: Spinach, Cauliflower, and Broccoli
\n\n
2. Foods Rich in Fibre
\n\n
With age, the walls of our gastrointestinal tract thicken which can lead to fewer
contractions and a slow digestive system. If ignored, this can result in severe constipation.
Having fibre-rich foods in old age promotes proper digestion and normalizes bowel
movements. Additionally, it helps to lower cholesterol, maintain blood sugar levels,
and prevent heart problems. Fibre-rich food to include in a diet chart for a person
in older age, include:
\n\n
  ● Fruits: Pear, Apple, Banana, Strawberry\n
  ● Vegetables: Beetroot, Spinach, Carrots, Cauliflower\n
  ● Whole grains: Wheat flour, Cornmeal flour, Gram flour, and Oats (Dalia).\n
  ● Other foods: Masoor Daal, Moong Daal, Almonds, Walnut, Nuts , Seeds
\n\n
3. Foods Rich in Calcium
\n\n
Bones become weak with age and having calcium-rich foods helps to meet the bodys calcium
requirements. If the requirement of calcium in the body is not met through diet, it starts to
absorb calcium from the bones. This makes them fragile and brittle, resulting in osteoporosis
which is common in old age. Here are some calcium-rich foods to include in an ideal diet plan
for people in older age.
\n\n
  ● Dairy products: Milk, Curd (Dahi), Cheese, Paneer, Buttermilk (Chach)\n
  ● Seeds: Sesame (til), Poppy (khus-khuss), Chia Seeds\n
  ● Sprouts: Moong, Masoor, and Chana\n
  ● Leafy greens and beans: Spinach (Palak), Coriander (Dhania), French Beans, Fenugreek
    (Methi), Broccoli
\n\n
4. Foods Rich in Iron
\n\n
Iron plays a vital role in the body by maintaining the count of haemoglobin that regulates
the flow of oxygen from the lungs to the rest of the body. The deficiency of iron is known as
anaemia which can result in a limited supply of oxygen, making you feel tired and lethargic.
Ensure an adequate amount of iron intake by including the following in an ideal diet chart for
senior citizens.
\n\n

  ● Vegetables: Beans, Spinach, Peas, Tomatoes, Potatoes, Beetroots\n
  ● Fruits: Banana, Apple, Pomegranate\n
  ● Nuts: Almond (Badam), Cashews (Kaju)
\n\n
5. Foods Rich in Vitamins
\n\n
An adequate amount of vitamins and minerals in the body help to prevent a number of health
problems, like heart ailments, cholesterol, blood pressure, diabetes, among others. Here are
some of the qualities of essential vitamins and their rich sources to include in a diet chart
for seniors.
\n\n

  ●  Vitamin C is known to have antioxidants that promote collagen building and prevent
     diseases like cancer. Rich sources include Potatoes, Orange, Lemon, Broccoli, Strawberry,
     Spinach, Cabbage, and Tomatoes.\n
  ●  Vitamin D is known to have properties that aid in the absorption of calcium in the body,
     thereby maintaining bone density and preventing osteoporosis in old age. Sources rich
     in Vitamin D, apart from sunlight, include Mushrooms, Milk, Dalia, Orange, Eggs, and
     certain types of fish.\n
  ●  Vitamin B12 is one of the most important nutrients of a healthy diet for an elderly
     person. This vitamin is a part of our DNA that makes red blood cells and keeps our
     nervous system running. While it is mostly found in lean meat, eggs, and fish, vegetarian
     alternatives include soya products, Curd (Dahi), low-fat milk, and cheese.
\n\n
6. Water to Stay Hydrated
\n\n
Elderly people are more likely to suffer from dehydration as their bodys ability to store
fluid becomes lower, further reducing the sense of feeling thirsty. However, this does not mean
that they do not need water anymore because it is an essential element that keeps the body running.
It also aids in better digestion and bowel movements, making it an important part of a healthy
diet plan for an elderly person. Experts recommend having 1.7 litres of water every 24 hours to
keep your body fully hydrated.


    </string>
    <string name="text2">
        There are five vaccines adults age 65 and older should consider to prevent certain diseases:
\n\n
1.Influenza (flu) vaccine\n
2.Pneumonia vaccine\n
3.Shingles vaccine\n
4.Tetanus, diphtheria and pertussis (Tdap) vaccine \n
5.COVID-19 vaccine\n\n

1.Influenza (Flu)\n
The influenza (flu) vaccine is recommended for everyone age 6 months and older every
year, starting in the fall. Influenza is a respiratory virus. Getting the vaccine
decreases your risk for developing complications from the flu, such as sinus and ear
infections, pneumonia, inflammation of the heart, brain or muscle tissues, multi-organ
failure or sepsis.\n
There are two vaccines that are particular for those age 65 and older because they
create a stronger immune response: high-dose flu vaccine and an adjuvanted flu vaccine.
You can get either of these vaccines in your health care provider’s office.\n\n

2.Pneumonia\n
The pneumonia vaccine is recommended as a one-time vaccine for people ages 65 and older.
Pneumonia is caused by a bacteria or virus that infects the lungs. The vaccine is 60
percent to 70 percent effective in preventing invasive disease. You can get this vaccine
in your health care provider’s office.\n\n

3.Shingles\n
The shingles vaccine is recommended for people age 50 and older even if you had shingles
in the past or had the previous shingles vaccine. It is a two-shot series, in which the
second shot is given two to six months after the first shot.
Shingles is a viral infection. The chicken pox virus remains inactive in your nerve tissue
and can reactivate as shingles, causing a painful, blistery rash on one side of the body.
Shingles can also cause postherpetic neuralgia (PHN), which causes severe and debilitating
pain where the rash occurred. The vaccine is greater than 90 percent effective in preventing
shingles and PHN. Supplies of this vaccine may be limited. Ask your health care provider or
a pharmacy about vaccine availability.\n\n

4.Tetanus, Diphtheria and Pertussis (Tdap)\n
The tetanus, diphtheria, and pertussis vaccine combined (Tdap) is recommended if you have
not received a tetanus shot in the last 10 years or have only had the tetanus and diphtheria
combined (Td) vaccine and not the Tdap in the past.
Tetanus is caused by a bacteria in soil, dirt and manure and can impair the nervous system.
Diphtheria is caused by a bacteria that attaches to the lining of the respiratory system,
which causes difficulty breathing and swallowing and can get into the bloodstream and damage
the heart, kidneys and nerves. Pertussis (whooping cough) can be a very serious disease, especially
for vulnerable populations, such as infants, young children and older adults. Pertussis causes
coughing fits due to the bacteria attaching to the lining of the upper respiratory system.
The vaccine is greater than 95 percent effective in preventing tetanus and diphtheria and 70
percent effective in preventing pertussis. You can get this vaccine from your health care provider.\n\n

5.COVID-19\n
The COVID-19 vaccine is recommended for ages 12 and older. The risk of severe illness from COVID-19
increases with age, so this is why the Centers for Disease Control recommends the COVID-19 vaccine
for older adults too. The COVID-19 vaccine helps prevent severe illness.\n
It typically takes two weeks after vaccination for the body to build immunity against the coronavirus
that causes COVID-19. You are not fully vaccinated until two weeks after the second dose of a two-dose
vaccine or two weeks after a one-dose vaccine. The two-dose vaccines are 94 percent to 95 percent
effective in preventing COVID-19. The one-dose vaccine is 66 percent effective. You can receive this
vaccine from a vaccination clinic set up expressly for this purpose or at a pharmacy.
    </string>
    <string name="text3">
        1. Get active\n
Physical activity is an immune system booster. The more you move, the more your
body is able to fight inflammation and infections.\n
The activity you partake in doesn not have to be strenuous. Low impact exercises
are effective, too.You might consider biking, walking, swimming, or low impact
aerobics. If you Are able to, engage in moderate intensity exercise for about
20 to 30 minutes a day to reach the recommended total of 150 minutes a weekTrusted
Source. Also, strengthen your muscles by lifting weights or doing yoga.
Modify your exercise routine to find what feels best for you.\n\n

2. Take supplements as necessary\n
Some supplements help support a healthy immune system. Before taking a supplement,
always ask your doctor if it is safe, especially if you are taking a prescription
medication. Some supplements they may recommend include calcium, vitamin D, vitamin
B6, or vitamin B12.Take supplements or multivitamins as instructed to boost your
immune system.\n\n

3. Eat a healthy diet\n
Diets rich in fruits, vegetables, and lean meats also give your immune system a
boost and protect against harmful viruses and bacteria that cause illnesses.
Fruits and vegetables are a good source of antioxidants. Antioxidants protect
your cells from damage and keep your body healthy.You should also limit your
consumption of sugary and fatty foods, which can trigger inflammation in the
body and lower your immune system.In addition, limit your intake of alcohol.
Ask your doctor about safe amounts of alcohol to drink per day or week.\n\n

4. Wash your hands frequently\n
Washing your hands on a regular basis is another excellent way to stay healthy
year-round. Viruses can live on surfaces for up to 24 hours. It is possible to
become ill if you touch a virus-covered surface and contaminate your hands, and
then touch your face.Wash your hands with warm soapy water often, and for at least
20 seconds. Avoid touching your nose, face, and mouth with your hands.
You can also protect yourself by using antibacterial hand sanitizer when you are unable
to wash your hands. Also, disinfect surfaces around your home and workstation frequently.\n\n

5. Learn how to manage stress\n
Chronic stress increases your body is production of the stress hormone cortisol.
Too much cortisol can disrupt different functions in your body, including your immune system.
To reduce stress, increase physical activity, get plenty of sleep, set reasonable
expectations for yourself, and explore relaxing, enjoyable activities.\n\n

6. Get plenty of rest\n
Not only can sleep reduce your stress level, but sleep is how your body repairs itself.
For this reason, getting an adequate amount of sleep can result in a stronger immune
system, making it easier for your body to fight off viruses.
Sleep is also important as you get older because it can improve memory and concentration.
Aim for at least seven and a half to nine hours of sleep per night.
If you have trouble sleeping, talk to your doctor to find the underlying cause. Causes
of insomnia can include inactivity during the day and too much caffeine. Or it can be a
sign of a medical condition like sleep apnea or restless leg syndrome.\n\n

7. Take steps to prevent infections\n
Getting annual vaccinations is another way to stay healthy throughout the year. If you are
age 65 and older, talk to your doctor about getting a high-dose or adjuvant flu vaccine.
Flu season is between October and May in the United States. It takes about two weeks
for the vaccine to be effective, and it reduces the risk of the flu by 40 to 60 percentTrusted
Source when the vaccine strains match the circulating strains.
The flu virus changes each year, so you should get the vaccine yearly. You can also talk to
your doctor about getting pneumococcal vaccines to protect against pneumonia and meningitis\n\n

8. Schedule annual physicals\n
Scheduling a yearly checkup can also keep you healthy. Always speak with your doctor if you
have concerns about your health.Conditions like diabetes and high blood pressure can go undetected.
Regular physical examinations will enable your doctor to diagnose any problems early. Getting
early treatment may prevent long-term complications.Also, if you have any cold or flu symptoms,
see your doctor immediately. The flu virus can lead to complications in adults over the age of 65.
The immune system weakens with age, making it harder to fight off the virus.
If you see a doctor within the first 48 hours of flu symptoms, they can prescribe an antiviral to
reduce the severity and length of symptoms.\n\n

9. Avoid contact with people who are sick\n
Another way to protect yourself year-round is to avoid being close to people who are sick.
This is easier said than done. But if there is a flu outbreak in your area, limit contact with
people who are not feeling well and avoid crowded areas until conditions improve.
If you must go out, protect yourself by wearing a face mask. If you are caring for someone with the
flu, wear a face mask and gloves, and wash your hands frequently.


    </string>
</resources>